The general environment in which I evolve is
私が活動する一般的な環境は、
the engine that can develop me.
私を成長させる原動力となります。
If I take a seed and put it in the fridge, not much will happen.
種を冷蔵庫に入れたら、あまり何も起こりません。
If I put it in the earth, there is light, sun, heat, it can develop.
土に植えれば、光、太陽、熱があり、成長することができます。
If you are in a complicated emotional or other environment, it will
もしあなたが感情的またはその他の複雑な環境にいるなら、それは
influence.
影響を与えるでしょう。
We know more and more that we can talk about the genetic egg and more and more that we talk about epigenetics.
私たちは遺伝子の卵についてますます話すようになり、エピジェネティクスについてますます話すようになっています。
the force of the environment represents almost 90% of
環境の力は、ほぼ90%を占めています。
this power.
この力のうち。
The question arises as to what environment your patient lives in.
患者さんがどのような環境で生活しているのかという疑問が生じます。
I very often ask the question, where do you live, what do you experience,
私はよく質問します。どこに住んでいますか、何を経験していますか、
what have you experienced, what are...
何を経験しましたか、何が...
It's all this anamnesis side, but with the idea of, I take a kind of layer
これはすべて病歴聴取の側面ですが、私は一種の層を
around and I see it.
周りに置いて、それを見ます。
what's happening. We need an environment to develop
何が起こっているのか。私たちは成長するために環境と、
and secondly
そして第二に、
space. To give space back to the mind, to give space back to the tissue,
空間が必要です。心に空間を取り戻し、組織に空間を取り戻し、
to give space back
空間を取り戻すこと。
to an emotion. Embryology is functional anatomy. And
感情に。発生学は機能解剖学です。そして、
what does that mean? It means
それは何を意味するのでしょうか？それは、
that it is anatomy that is first in motion. Second, it
まず、動きのある解剖学であるということです。第二に、それは
is anatomy that uses
使用する解剖学です。
the four years.
4つの年。
five dimensions we know, up, down, left, etc. And the fourth dimension
私たちが知っている5つの次元、上、下、左など。そして第4の次元は、
which is the notion of chronos, of time. You will have to be able to look at this
クロノス、時間の概念です。あなたはこの小さな胚が、
little embryo developing through all its movements and also with sections. This
そのすべての動きと、さらに断面図でどのように発達するかを見ることができる必要があります。この
notion is memory. This notion of time is also a notion of memory,
概念は記憶です。この時間の概念は記憶の概念でもあり、
that is to say that you carry time within you. You are a concentration
つまり、あなたは自分の中に時間を持っています。あなたは時間の集中体です。
of time. And
そして、
sometimes in the body there are specific areas.
時には体の中に特定の領域が存在します。
which are concentrated areas where the person is blocked.
それは、その人がブロックされている集中した領域です。
A word, a gesture, a look can block a person for their whole life.
言葉、ジェスチャー、視線が、人の人生を一生ブロックすることがあります。
And sometimes, this time is found in the tissues.
そして時には、それが組織の中に、この時間として見つかることがあります。
And sometimes, you can work, you've already noticed,
そして時には、あなたはすでに気づいているかもしれませんが、
you've done some work, and then all of a sudden,
あなたは仕事をしていて、突然、
there's an emotional release that happens.
感情的な解放が起こります。
You have, in fact, released a concentration.
あなたは実際には集中を解放したのです。
You put it back in its space.
あなたはそれをその空間に戻します。
And that, in embryology, is important.
そして、これは発生学において重要です。
Because we will be able to find these notions.
なぜなら、これらの概念を見つけることができるからです。
If you remember the short film we saw this morning,
今朝見た短い映画を思い出していただければ、
you saw that there were movements where we moved forward,
前進する動きと、
and then all of a sudden, movements where it moved back.
突然後退する動きがあるのがお分かりいただけたでしょう。
Movements as if there was a wave, like that.
まるで波のような動きです。
But if you observe that, if there is a movement like that,
しかし、もしそのような動きがあるなら、
it means there are points of support.
そこには支点があるはずです。
And we will use them as therapeutic tools.
そして、私たちはそれらを治療の道具として利用します。
Because the body knows these points of support.
なぜなら、体はその支点を知っているからです。
If you give them a good point of support,
もし良い支点を与えれば、
and it knows where it can develop, it can rebuild itself.
体はどこから発達し、再構築できるかを知っています。
There is the notion that you have time, that there are tissues, that there are fluids,
時間、組織、体液という概念があり、
and everything is expressed in a constellation,
そのすべてが星座のように表現され、
we say that mind, body, spirit are united.
心、体、精神は一体であると言われています。
Mind, body, spirit.
心、体、精神。
So osteopathy is a science based on the art of touch,
オステオパシーは触診の芸術に基づいた科学であり、
which offers true knowledge of the living heart,
生きた心の真の知識を提供します。
the one that tells the story of anatomy,
それは解剖学の歴史を語り、
linked to the movement of spirit and mind.
精神と心の動きと結びついています。
One of the goals of osteopathy is to improve exchanges
オステオパシーの目的の一つは、交換を改善し、
and to have an impact down to the cellular level,
細胞レベルにまで影響を与えることです。
and even, I think we go further,
さらに、私たちはもっと深く、
that we have impacts even on the genetic level.
遺伝子レベルにまで影響を与えていると考えています。
We now prove it by the phenomena of tensegrity
テンセグリティ現象や
and the phenomena of epigenetics,
エピジェネティクス現象によって、
that in fact we have a very profound impact, and we will see how far it goes. The path... My professor, my teacher, had suggested to me, first told me that you must study embryology. He tells me that when you understand embryology well, you will understand what anatomy means. Anatomy will give you physiology. This physiology, you will also have to study its pathos. Its pathophysiology. Then we have psychology, then we have philosophy. Finally, there is spirituality. How conception develops, and where it is how I die. That death...
実際には非常に深い影響を与えていることが証明されており、
Its pathophysiology.
その病態生理学です。
Then we have psychology, then we have philosophy.
そして心理学があり、哲学があります。
Finally, there is spirituality.
最終的には、精神性があります。
How conception develops, and where it is how I die.
受胎がどのように発達し、そして私がどのように死ぬか。
That death...
死が...
on a developmental level
発達の観点から
is useful.
有用であること。
If there is no cellular death,
もし細胞死がなければ、
I don't like the word death,
私は「死」という言葉が好きではありませんが、
I would always say transformation.
常に変容だと言えるでしょう。
It is a continuous transformation.
それは絶え間ない変容です。
This power that was already established
最初の細胞にすでに確立されていたこの力は、
in the first cell,
最初の細胞に、
It continues until the end of your life.
あなたの人生の終わりまで続きます。
Until your last breath.
最後の息をひきとるまで。
That is, you have this capacity
つまり、あなたにはこの能力があります。
to take the breath of life.
生命の息吹を取り入れる能力が。
the breath of life is there
生命の息吹はそこにあって、
and then I breathe out
そして私は息を吐き出し、
and I still have
そしてまだ
the energy to
再び息を吸い込むための
take it again
エネルギーがあります。
so I can still participate
だから私はまだ参加できます。
and we do that every time, that's where we have the transformation
そして私たちは毎回そうします。そこに変容があります。
I think sometimes people
時々人々は
they are stuck in time
時間の中に閉じ込められていると思います。
and that they sometimes come to get
そして時々、それについての情報を得るために来るのです。
information about it
それについての情報を得るために。
very often people when they follow
これらのコースを受講する人々は非常に多く、その後、実践の中で
these courses, afterwards in practice
これらのコースを受講した後、実践の中で
something happens
何かが起こります。
because
なぜなら、
we go into something where no mind can intervene,
私たちは、精神が介入できない領域へと入っていくからです。
but there is a modification that happens inside.
しかし、内部で変化が起こります。
Because we will see the development of the perfect embryo, as they say.
なぜなら、私たちは完璧な胚の発生を見るからです。
We will be in the blueprint, which keeps its median line, which has no deviation.
私たちは、正中線を保ち、逸脱のないブループリントの中にいます。
This is my birth, this is the space of my conception.
それが私の誕生であり、私の受胎の空間です。
And sometimes you have the median line here, you are in the right axis.
そして時には、ここに正中線があり、あなたは正しい軸にいます。
Sometimes you can already deviate at your conception.
時には、受胎の時点で既に逸脱していることもあります。
be deviated at your birth, you can be deviated by a trauma.
誕生時に逸脱していることもあれば、トラウマによって逸脱していることもあります。
And we must recognize
そして、これらの点を
these points.
認識する必要があります。
Non-recognition
認識しないことは、
develops all
あらゆる代償活動を
compensatory activities.
発展させます。
So I must, at some point,
だから、私はある時点で、
by the quality of my presence,
私の存在の質によって、
by the quality of touch,
触れることの質によって、
by what the tissue will inform you,
組織があなたに伝えることによって、
be able to recognize
これらの空間を
these spaces.
認識できるようになること。
And there, he can have
そして、そこに
a...
修正の
a trust
信頼が
of correction
あるかもしれません。
you just have to be present
あなたはただそこに存在し、
for the touch
それに触れるだけでいいのです。
because there is no will
なぜなら、意志がないからです。
that's what's really important
これが本当に重要なことです。
the body has a capacity for self-regulation
体には自己調整能力があり、
of self-regulation
自己調整し、
and to maintain its health
健康を維持する能力があります。
and so this notion of strength
したがって、この自然の
of nature
力の概念は、
is to reconnect with that
それと再接続することです。
we see very well
私たちはよくわかります。
if now there is no more human impact
もし今、人間の影響がなければ、
nature quickly reclaims its rights and we have been somewhat cut off from
自然は非常に迅速にその権利を完全に回復します。そして私たちはそれから少し切り離されてしまいました。この発達において、自然はそこにあります。私たちが介入しなければしないほど、
that. As long as this development is there, nature is there. The less we intervene, the better
良いのです。もう一つの
it is. Another
原則は、構造と機能の相互関係の概念であり、
principle is the notion of reciprocity of structure and function and
これらの原則の
all of
全体は、体がこれらすべてを考慮に入れる必要があり、
these principles is that the body, you have to take all of this into account and
したがって、
therefore become aware
私がこれを使用できることを認識することです。
that I can use that.
これは本当に実用的です。
It's really practical.
彼にはこの力があるのです。
That it has this power.
そして彼は何を求めているのでしょうか？
And what does it ask for?
それは単に調整されることです。
It's simply that it be adjusted.
小さな指を専門とする医師がいます。
There are doctors who specialize in little fingers.
素晴らしいことです。
It's great.
同時に、彼らは例えば下肢や上肢だけを見ているわけではありません。
At the same time, they don't see that the lower limb, for example, or upper,
それは腹膜嚢の拡張です。
is an expansion of a peritoneal sac.
原子は分子を形成します。
Atoms will form molecules.
分子は細胞を形成します。
Molecules will form cells.
細胞は組織を形成します。
Cells form tissues.
組織は臓器を形成します。
Tissues form organs.
したがって、最終的に私は
So, ultimately, I am a kind of package
あなたの前にいる動く原子の塊のようなものです。
And before the atom, there is also this whole notion of energy.
Et avant l'atome, il y a aussi toute cette notion d'énergie.
So, ultimately, what we perceive is a set of energies.
Donc, finalement, ce qu'on perçoit, c'est un ensemble d'énergie.
It's a package of energy that sometimes needs to be a bit structural.
C'est un paquet d'énergie qui a besoin, parfois, d'être un peu structurel.
Which thinks, moreover.
Qui pense, en plus.
Onto, Genesis.
Onto, Genèse.
Onto, that means being.
Onto, ça veut dire être.
And Genesis, that means formation.
Et Genèse, ça veut dire la formation.
Ontogenesis is the formation of a being.
L'ontogénèse, c'est la formation d'un être.
We will study the ontogenesis of man.
Nous, on va étudier l'ontogénèse de l'homme.
And especially in its morphogenesis.
Et surtout dans sa morphogénétique.
So in its morph, in its form, and
Donc  dans  sa  morphe,  dans  sa  forme,  et
the formation of this form.
la  formation  de  cette  forme.
An individual.
Un individu.
Phylogenesis, that covers the history of the development of all species.
La phylogénèse, ça reprend l'histoire du développement de toutes les espèces.
through time. We will study human ontogenesis. We will especially
travers  du  temps.  On  va  étudier  l 'ontogénèse  humaine.  On  va  surtout
look for the form
rechercher  la  forme
and this power of human development and see the impacts we can have
et cette puissance du développement de l'être humain et voir les impacts qu'on peut avoir
in practice.
au niveau de la pratique.